Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
- Individual Framed Items
  - Salinas, Cal. [with vignettes of King City and Castroville, California]., 1891; Elliott Pub. Co.; BANC PIC 19xx.191--D; 1 print: lithograph; sheet 54 x 72 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed key to locations in central image (LR and LL). Printed (LC in image): The Elliott Pub. Co. 120 Sutter St. S.F
    Content/DescriptionCentral image is overview of the town of Salinas, and distant hills. Marginal images of businesses, public buildings and residences in and near Salinas include Jeffery House, pubic school, City Restaurant, J.W. Tholcke residence, 3 Vanderhurst & Sanborn, Co. stores (one in King City), Monterey County Bank, St. James Hotel (in Castroville), Central Milling Co., court house, Berges & Garrissere wholesale liquor dealers, Salinas Hotel, Salinas Index printing office, Odd Fellows block, Monterey Planing Mill, Iverson Bro[ther]s agricultural works, Railroad Exchange Hotel (King City), bird's-eye view of King City, J. Quigg residence, M.F. Walsh residence (Castroville).
    Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; Salinas (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; King City (Calif.)
  - Birds eye view of Healdsburg, Cal[ifornia]., 1876; Glover, E.S.; A.L. Bancroft & Company; Jordan Bros.; BANC PIC 19xx.180--D; 1 print: lithograph, b&w; sheet 44 x 62 cm. Printed title (C). Printed (CL out side of image): Published by Jordan Bros., Proprietors of the "Russian River Flag."; (CR): Entered according to act of Congress in the year 1876 by Jordan Bros., in the office of the Librarian of Congress at Washington, D.C.; (LL): drawn by E. S. Glover; (LR): A.L. Bancroft & Co., Lith., S.F.
    Top image is overview of Healdsburg to the northwest; some streets and buildings identified by printed letters and numbers, but key to these is lacking. Bottom images are Russian River valley (center), and four small vignettes of Litton's Springs, Skagg's Springs, Magnolia Farm, and Geyser Springs.
    Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; Healdsburg (Calif.)
  - Graphic chart of the City & County of San Francisco [California, with explanatory references]., 1878; c1875; Britton & Rey; BANC PIC 19xx.041:99--D; 1 print on paper: lithograph; sheet 60.5 x 80 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): Lith. by Britton, Rey & Co. S.F.; (LC above title): Explanatory reference figures to the "news letter" graphic chart [followed by list of items 1-188]; (LR): The extreme distance from county line on the south to Black Point on the north is 8 1/2 miles; from Water Front on the east to Cliff House on the west is 8 miles; (LR): Entered according to act of Congress by F. Marriott, in the office of the Librarian in Washington, D.C., 1875; (LC above title): San Francisco News Letter, California Advertiser; (LC below title): Respectfully dedicated to the leading interests of California & the Pacific Coast by Frederick Marriott, revised March 1878.
    Bird's-eye view looking southwest from bay across city to Pacific Ocean and down peninsula; waterfront area with numerous ships (steamships, sidewheel steamships, sailboats, sailing ships, ferries, etc.) in dock and on bay near wharves in foreground; Golden Gate in right distance.
    San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Waterfronts -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; Vessels
  - San Jose, 1856, county of Santa Clara, Cal[iforni]a., Kuchel & Dresel; Britton & Rey; BANC PIC 19xx.179--D; 1 print: lithograph, 2 colors; sheet 57 x 70 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LC below title): This City is situated in the beautiful & fertile valley of San Jose, about 50 miles south of San Francisco. It contains a population of about 3000 persons, engaged chiefly in agricultural & horticultural pursuits. This valley is well supplied with water from artesian wells, there being no less than 60 within the city & 120 within a circumference of 6 miles. One of these wells discharges a column of water 22 feet in height, 7 inches in thickness, & supplies 3600 gallons pr. minute. These wells vary in depth from 60 to 300 ft. & in temperature from 60 to 69 degrees. The climate is very salubrious, being one of the most desirable places for a residence. Within a pleasant ride of 14 miles are the rich Quicksilver Mines, & the celebrated medicinal Soda Springs of New Almaden. Published by Kuchel & Dresel, 176 Clay St. San Francisco. Printed (LL): Drawn from nature & on stone by Kuchel & Dresel; (LR): Printed by Britton & Rey, S.F.
    Content/DescriptionLarge central view of town surrounded by 22 vignettes of businesses, public buildings and residences including: city hall, J. Belden residence, Al Buen Gusto (Casimir Clauzel [store?]), Jno. H. Moore residence, El Dorado (J.E. Knoche variety store), [David] McLellan's Hotel and store, [Frank] Lightson's Block, D.J. Porter residence, Levi Goodrich residence, J.B. Bontemps nursery, Samuel J. Hensley residence, A.J. Grayson residence, James F. Kennedy residence (Stockton Ranch), V.D. Moody residence, L. Archer residence, Levi P. Peck, residence, Clinton House, James R. Lowe residence, San Jose Hotel with restaurant and oyster saloon, J.C. Cobb residence, A La Mariposa (E. Auzerais & Bros. [store?]), L Prevost's flower garden (San Jose Nursery). At bottom, 2 large vignettes of Young Ladies' Academy, on either side of block of descriptive text.
    Lithographs -- Color; Bird's-eye views; San Jose (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Placerville (Hangtown), El Dorado County, California., c1851; Whitford, John; Justh & Co.; Bee, Albert W.; BANC PIC 1980.067--A; 1 print (pictorial lettersheet): lithograph, b&w; 21 x 26 cm.
    Pictorial lettersheet view of Placerville from hillside looking east.
    Lithographs; Pictorial lettersheets; Placerville (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Cityscapes -- California -- Placerville
- Collections of Framed Items
  - Items from: Views related to Hubert Howe Bancroft and the Bancroft Library in San Franccisco, ca. 1880-ca. 1947; BANC PIC 1905.11567-.11569, BANC PIC 1905.11574--PIC
    - Valencia Street Library Reading Room & Mr. Bancroft's Study, San Francisco, Unknown Artist & Schmidt, A.; BANC PIC 1905.11567a-c--FR
    - Bancroft Library at 1538 Valencia Street, San Francisco: First Floor and Exterior, Unknown; BANC PIC 1905.11568--FR & 1905.11574--FR
    - Bancroft Building, 721 Market Street, San Francisco (1859-1906), BANC PIC 1905.11569--FR; 2 drawings mounted in a single frame; bottom: ink and pencil on paper (finished drawing); top: gouache and pencil on paper (sketch)
  - Sketches of San Francisco, Benicia, and Mexico City, 1849-1851.; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:01-11--ALB
    - [Clay and Montgomery Streets, San Francisco, Calif], [ca. 1851]; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:01--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 20.7 x 23.1 cm. Street names indicated in image.
      Content/DescriptionCommercial street lined with businesses including New York Shirt Depot and Keith & Jenkins Drugs and Medicines. Pedestrians and a horse and wagon on street; numerous masts of ships moored in bay visible in distance.
      San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Pencil works; Cityscapes -- California -- San Francisco; Commercial buildings -- California -- San Francisco Bay Area
    - [San Francisco from Telegraph Hill], 1851; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:02--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 22.7 x 35.2 cm. Handwritten (LR on mount): View of San Francisco 1851.
      View from signal hill looking towards Yerba Buena harbor filled with masted ships. Few scattered buildings and figures in foreground; San Francisco Bay stretching off in the distance.
      Drawings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Pencil works
    - View above Benicia [Calif.]; Govt property, 1851; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:03--fALB; 1 drawing on tinted paper: pencil; 24 x 38.3 cm. Handwritten title and date (verso).
      Large building in open landscape surrounded by smaller outbuildings. Ships on water in distance.
      Drawings; Pencil works; Benicia (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Benicia, California; looking down the river], 1850; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:04--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 21.5 x 35.5 cm. Handwritten (verso): Benicia California, sketched 1850 / by D. W. Coit / looking down the river.
      Distant view from water looking towards the harbor and town of Benicia (former capital of California). Numerous masted ships and Carquinez Strait in distance.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Drawings; Pencil works; Benicia (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; San Francisco Bay Area (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Government property and residence of Colonel Allen, Benicia, Calif.], [1851]; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:05--fALB; 1 drawing on tinted paper: pencil; 24.1 x 35.2 cm. Handwritten (verso): The Gov r property & Col. Allens residence (Benicia) / sketched by D. W. Coit.
      Open landscape with large buildings in the distance and at right, a small shack in the center, and Carquinez Strait at far right.
    - Valley near San Joseph [San Jose?], Cal., [ca. 1849]; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:06--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 24.2 x 34.9 cm. Handwritten title (verso).
      Broad valley with oak trees; foothills in distance.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- California
    - Village [Vallejo?] above Benicia, 1851; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:07--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 24.9 x 35.5 cm. Handwritten title and date (verso).
      Distant view of village (Vallejo?) showing numerous buildings on distant shore and a wooden dock or boardwalk with oxen-drawn wagon in foreground.
      Pencil works; Sketches
    - San Francisco [looking toward the Golden Gate], [1849]; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:08--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 23.9 x 35.2 cm.
      View looking northwest from slope of Signal or Telegraph Hill. Black Point visible in distance. Scattered houses and buildings below slope.
      San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- San Francisco; Pencil works; Sketches
    - Portsmouth Plaza looking north [sic -- probably looking east], 1849; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:09--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 25.6 x 36.1 cm. Handwritten (LL margin): San Francisco Co., 1849 - Plaza by D. W. Coit; (UC): Genl Geary ([?] Governor of Pen.) Alcaldi; (LL): Old Adobe build. / custom house; (LC): Plaza / [which?] house / rent $130,000 [?] per annum; (LR): First Church / Rev. M. Williams.
      View across Portsmouth Square from an open field with the Custom House in the center and masted ships in the bay. Yerba Buena Island in distance.
    - [Church interior] Chapel in San Domingo Mexico, 1848-1849; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:10--fALB (verso); 1 drawing: pencil; 35.5 x 25.2 cm. Handwritten (LL): Chappel [sic.] in San Domingo Mexico 1848 by D. W. Coit; (LL running vertically): For Mrs. Phoebe A. Hearst / with the kind regards of / D. C. Gilman / Pleasanton / Oct. 27. 1899 / An original drawin [sic.] by my uncle / Daniel W. Coit sketched in / [the?] open air in 1849: - & given to me by him.
      Unfinished sketch of the east end interior of the chapel showing the altar.
    - San Francisco [looking toward harbor and ships], 1849; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:10--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil; 25.2 x 35.5 cm. Handwritten (LL): San Francisco 1849 - by D. W. Coit.
      View looking at Yerba Buena Bay from upper Market Street showing numerous dwellings and buildings, several masted ships moored in the bay with Yerba Buena Island in the distance.
      San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Dwellings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works; Cityscapes -- California -- San Francisco; Sketches
    - [San Domingo Church and Convent, Mexico City], [1848-1849]; Coit, Daniel Wadsworth; BANC PIC 1899.001:11--fALB; 1 drawing: pencil and ink wash; 21.5 x 38 cm.
      Sketches
  - Mining, Indians, and other views around Vallecito, Calaveras Co., Cal., ca. 1853; Baker, Isaac W.; BANC PIC 1942.004:01-04--FR
    - [Group of Digger Indians], [1853?]; Baker, Isaac W.; BANC PIC 1942.004:01--FR; 1 painting on linen: oil?; 203 x 190 cm.
      Caption provided by donor, Frederick S. Baker: Group of Digger Indians painted ... by Isaac W. Baker
      Group portrait of five Digger Indians: three women -- two carrying baskets on their heads --, a man with a walking stick, and a boy with a bow.
      Indians of North America -- California -- Calaveras County -- Portraits; Paintings
    - [Map of Vallecita Flat], 1853; Baker, Isaac W.; BANC PIC 1942.004:02--FR; 1 painting on linen: oil?; 188 x 181 cm. Painted title (UC on bar): Vallecita.
      Caption provided by donor, Frederick S. Baker: Map of Vallicita (Vallecita) Flat in the summer of 1853.
      Map of area near Murphy's Camp showing mining prospects, veins of gold, waterways, settlements, and landmarks. Among buildings on the road to Murphy's Camp: D. Seeley Blacksmith, and Baker's caravan wagon labeled "Daguerreotypes."
      Paintings; Murphys (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Vallecito (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Gold mines and mining -- California -- Calaveras County -- Maps
    - [Limestone caves in the vicinity of Vallecito], 1853; Baker, Isaac W.; BANC PIC 1942.004:03--FR; 1 painting on linen: oil?; 185 x 179 cm. Printed (UL margin): I.W.B.
      Caption provided by donor, Frederick S. Baker: First exploration of one of the limestone caves in the vicinity of Vallicita (now spelled Vallecito).
      Interior of limestone cavern with stalagmites hanging from cavern ceiling. Four miners (possibly successive views of two men) with candles and skulls exploring cavern and using tree trunk ladders.
      Paintings; Vallecito (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Caves -- California -- Vallecito
    - [Calaveras Big Trees], 1853; Baker, Isaac W.; BANC PIC 1942.004:04--FR; 1 painting on linen: oil?; 185 x 176 cm.
      Caption provided by donor, Frederick S. Baker: Calaveras Big Trees in 1853 showing the tree that had been recently felled, upon the stump of which the dance hall was later constructed.
      View of forest showing fallen giant, dance floor and cabin. Man in cabin and standing on giant, and two others measuring the dance floor, with horse in foreground. Sign on fallen giant reads: "All persons are forbid taking any wood from this tree".
      Paintings; Redwoods -- California
  - Portraits of notable printers, 17th-19th century; BANC PIC 1973.018--FR; 11 items: b&w; various sizes.
    - Robert Etienne, BANC PIC 1973.018:01-FR; 1 print: etching, hand colored; visible image 26.5 x 17.2 cm. Printed (LL): C. Jacquand; (LR): Leclerc sc.; (LC): Robert Etienne.
      Full length portrait of 15th century printer with type box, ink blotters and books.
      Portraits; Printers -- Portraits
    - Joan [John] Michael Fleischman, 1769; BANC PIC 1973.018:02-FR; 1 print: etching; visible image 17.1 x 10.5 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LR): C. V. Noorde F. 1769.
      Half length seated portrait of man wearing tir-cornered hat seated with tools of type sculpting trade infront of him.
    - Balthasar Moretus Antuerpiensis [NOS], BANC PIC 1973.018:03-FR
    - Joseph Moxon, BANC PIC 1973.018:05-FR; 1 print: etching; 14.1 x 81 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LL): F.H. Vanhove. sculp.
      Bust portrait of 17th century printer set in an oval, titles of his works visible above his portrait. His birth date and place noted on the plinth (Wakefield August 8 1627).
    - William Caslon, BANC PIC 1973.018:06--FR; 1 print: etching; 14.5 x 9.8 cm. Printed title (LC).
      Bust portrait in oval set on plinth.
    - Christophorus Plantinus Turonensis, BANC PIC 1973.018:08-FR; 1 print: etching; visible image 18.7 x 14 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LR): E. Boulonois fecit.
    - Paolo Manuzio, BANC PIC 1973.018:09-FR; 1 print: engraving; image 12 x 10 cm on sheet 27.1 x 20.1 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LL): G. Longh: dis; (LR): F. Zuliani inc.
      Bust length profile portrait of bearded man wearing cap.
    - Giambattista Bodoni, BANC PIC 1973.018:10-FR; 1 print: engraving; image 11.8 x 9.7 on sheet 27.2 x 20 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): Per N. Bettoni; (LR): G. Mussi dis. ed. inc.
    - Joannes Enschede, 1768; BANC PIC 1973.018:12-FR; 1 print: etching; 17.6 x 11.1 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LC): Letter gieter en Boekdrukker. / Gebooren den 10 Juny 1708. in Haarlem. Printed signature (LR): CV Noorde, a.d. V iv del.& Fe. 1768.
      Half length seated portrait of 18th century book maker.
    - [View of Nuremberg from Nuremberg Chronicle], BANC PIC 1973.018:17-FR; 1 print (double leaf) on paper: woodcut and letterpress; visible image 40.7 x 60.4 cm. Printed (UC): Nuremberga.
      View of Nurenberg with Stromer's paper mill in foreground.
      Nuremberg chronicle -- Pictorial works; Woodcuts
    - A True and Exact Representation of the Art of Crafting & Preparing Letters for Printing, 1750; Hinton, John; Universal Magazine; BANC PIC 1973.018:18-FR; 1 print: engraving; 20.4 x 23.5 cm. Printed title (UC). Printed (LC): Engrav'd for the Universal Magazine 1750 for J.Hinton at the Kings Arms in St. Pauls Church Yard London. Handwritten (LC): The views represent the interior of Wm. Caslon's Foundry in 1750.The workmen marked (3) is Jos: Jackson & (4) Thos. Cottrell.
      Interior of workshop showing men and young boys at forges and worktables creating letterpress type.
      Printing presses -- Pictorial works; Engravings
  - Drawings of California and Mexico, ca. 1850-ca. 1858; Emmert, Paul; BANC PIC 1974.002--FR; 12 drawings on paper: pencil and pastel; ca. 3 1/2 x 6 1/2 in
    - Five views of Mexico, ca. 1850-ca. 1858.; Emmert, Paul E.; BANC PIC 1974.002:1-5--FR; 5 drawings (1 frame)
    - Three Views of California, ca. 1850-ca. 1858.; Emmert, Paul E.; BANC PIC 1974.002:6-8--FR; 3 drawings (1 frame)
    - Maison de Sante de la Societe Francaise de bienfaisance Mutuelle, San Francisco, [ca. 1850-ca. 1858]; Emmert, Paul E.; BANC PIC 1974.002:9--FR; 1 drawing: pencil and pastel; 13 x 17 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): P. Emmert. Handwritten title (label below image).
      Large brick hospital building with a water tower to the right. The French Hospital was founded in 1851 and incorporated in 1856 by the French Mutual Benevolent Society (San Francisco, Calif.)
      Drawings; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Pastels (Visual works); Maison de sant/ac\e de la Societe -- Pictorial works
    - La Mission Dolores [firis?] San Francisco, California, [ca. 1850-ca. 1858]; Emmert, Paul E.; BANC PIC 1974.002:10--FR; 1 drawing: pencil and pastel; 12.2 x 16 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): P. Emmert / 1858. Handwritten title (LC on label).
      Eastern façade of mission building.
      Drawings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - Mouillage de Mazatlan and Mazatlan, Mexique, Emmert, Paul; BANC PIC 1974.002:11-12--FR
  - Portraits of Californians: by Leola Hall Coggins, ca. 1900-ca. 1920?; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012--FR and BANC PIC 1905.17134:226-:232--PIC; 14 paintings and drawings: some oil; various sizes
    - [David Starr Jordan], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:226--B; 1 sketch on prepared canvas: pencil; irreg. image 39 x 36.7 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leola Hall / Coggins.
      Bust portrait of Jordan (1851-1931); a naturalist, scholar, and political commentator.
    - Portrait of Edwin Markham, [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:227--FR; 1 painting: oil; 48.5 x 36 cm. Painted signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins. Note on canvas (verso): Edwin Markham, 1852-1940 by Leola Hall Coggins.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Markham, Edwin, -- 1852-1940. -- Portraits
    - [David Starr Jordan], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:228--B; 1 painting on canvas mounted on cardboard: oil; 37 x 31.7 cm. Painted signature (LR).
      Profile portrait of Jordan (1851-1931); a naturalist, scholar, and political commentator.
    - Joaquin Miller, [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:229--AX; 1 painting on board: oil; 30.2 x 25.3 cm. Painted signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins. Title from label on verso. Inventory stamp (verso): Oct. 1951 (#785).
      Bust portrait of Miller wearing a dark, broad-brimmed hat.
    - [Joaquin Miller], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:230--B; 1 sketch on prepared canvas: pencil; irreg. image 45 x 33 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leola Hall / Coggins.
      Bust portrait of Miller wearing a dark, broad-brimmed hat. Prepatory sketch for BANC PIC 1905.17134:229--AX.
    - [Herbert L. Coggins], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:231--B; 1 drawing on cardboard: pencil; 45 x 35.2 cm. Handwritten (verso): Coggins / Leola Hall Coggins.
      Profile portrait of Herbert Leonard Coggins (1881- ) wearing pince-nez glasses. Socialist candidate for U.S. Representative from California 6th District, 1924.
    - Emporer Norton?, [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1905.17134:232--AX; 1 drawing on paper mounted on mat board: charcoal, chalk, and ink wash; 35.3 x 26.4 cm. Typed title (label on verso, LR). Inventory stamp (verso): Oct. 1951 (#791). Provenance information on verso.
      Bust portrait of Joshua Abraham Norton (1819-1880); an Englishman who came to America during the California Gold Rush and declared himself Norton I, Emperor of the United States and Protector of Mexico.
    - [Portrait of David Starr Jordan], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:1--FR; 1 painting: oil; 66.2 x 51 cm.
      Unfinished bust length portrait.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Jordan, David Starr, -- 1851-1931. -- Portraits
    - [Portrait of Henry Bashford Smith], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:2--FR; 1 painting: oil; 66.5 x 51 cm. Painted signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins. Incised signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins.
      Oil paintings; Portraits
    - [Portrait of Edwin Markham], 1915; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:3--FR; 1 painting: oil; 66.2 x 51.2 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): Leola Hall Coggins / 1915. Incised signature (LL): Leola Hall Coggins.
    - [Portrait of Mrs. Joaquin Leland Miller], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:4--FR; 1 painting: oil; 66.2 x 51 cm. Painted signature (LL): Leola H. Coggins.
    - [Portrait of George Wharton James], [ca. 1900-ca. 1920?]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:5--FR; 1 painting: oil; 66.2 x 50.7 cm. Painted signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins.
      Bust length profile portrait.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; James, George Wharton, -- 1858-1923 -- Portraits
    - [William Keith], [ca. 1900- ca. 1920]; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012:6--C; 1 painting on academy board: oil; 51.5 x 40 cm. Painted signature (LR): Leola Hall Coggins. Typed label (verso): William Keith, 1839-1911 / by Leola Hall Coggins. Inventory stamp (verso): Oct. 1951 (#823).
      Bust length, three-quarter profile portrait based on photograph of the artist William Keith (1838-1911).
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Keith, William, -- 1838-1911. -- Portraits
    - [August Vollmer], [19--]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1946.012:7-C; 1 painting on canvas mounted on gypsum board: oil; 52.7 x 43 cm. Painted signature (LL): Leola Hall Coggins.
      Bust length portrait of Vollmer (1876-1955).